JESSICA AU SOFTWARE ENGINEER

■ au.jessica.m@gmail.com

oportfolio/

(916)897-6417

in jessica-m-au

(7) jessica-au

I am an educator turned fullstack developer who maintains a strong passion for teaching and utilizing my critical thinking skills to solve tough problems. I value developing tools that augment and transform the user experience, and I hope to lend my prior experience to the development of tools and applications that are elegant and thoughtfully designed.

Skills

JavaScript

React.js

Redux

Express

Node.js

Python

Django

PostgreSQL

Sequelize.js

MongoDB

Heroku

HTML

CSS

Selenium

Postman

Bootstrap

Sass

Ruby

Mongoose

Atlas

Github

Git

Socket.io

Volunteering

Asian American Pacific Islander Club - EGHS Faculty Adviser Elk Grove, CA

Projects

Messenger - FullStack Software Engineer

June 2021 to July 2021

A full fledge chat application | Stack: React, Redux, Express, Node, Sockets Responsibilities:

- Improved authentication security through json web tokens
- Implemented new feature following design and specification requirement
- •. Optimized codebase for scalability

Profile Search Engine - Frontend Developer

June 2021 to June 2021

An application that allows tagging and searching personal profiles | React, Node, HTML, CSS

- Built features which utilized public API
- Implemented mobile-first UI

Selene - FullStack Software Engineer

Mar. 2021 to Apr. 2021

An e-commerce application focused on user experience and inventory management. | Stack: Python, Django, PostgreSQL, Heroku

Responsibilities:

- · Designed and built out backend relational models and database
- Implemented inventory management library
- · Built out and styled product and shopping cart features

NipponRunner - FullStack Software Engineer

Feb. 2021 to Mar. 2021

An online language learning application designed to help users learn hiragana, the Japanese alphabet. | Stack: React, Express, MongoDB, Node, Heroku, Atlas

Responsibilities:

- Collaborated with teammate to develop application concept and game logic continuity
- Built logic for backend routes and algorithms for frontend game logic
- · Seeded database, managed features/branches, code conflicts and pull requests, and deployment

Bin Media Res - Software Engineer

Feb. 2021 to Feb. 2021

An online media category application designed to help organize your favorite podcasts. | Stack: Javascript, Express, SQL, Node.js, Heroku

Responsibilities:

- · Built out frontend user interface and backend routes, associations, and models
- Utilized podcast API for user content

Mathblaster - UX/UI Designer

Jan. 2021 to Jan. 2021

A fun and engaging learning application paying homage to the late '90s game of the same name. | Stack: HTML, CSS, Javascript

Responsibilities:

· Built out interactive frontend application utilizing javascript algorithms and logic, and managed git workflow

Education

General Assembly 2020 to 2021

Software Engineering Immersive Program

California State University-Sacramento 2014 to 2015

SB 2042 Teaching Credential with English Learner Authorization in English

University of California, Berkeley 2006 to 2011

Bachelor of Arts English

Employment

Tutoring Club · Lead Tutor · Folsom, CA

2018 to 2020

Prepared high school students for the reading, writing, and essay sections of the PSAT, SAT, ACT, AP English Language, and AP English composition tests, often to results of 150% improvement or greater

Pearson · Educator Testing Essay Scorer · Sacramento, CA

2016 to 2016

Holistically scored hundreds of essays daily on tests such as CBEST, CSET – English, Washington Basic Skills, CTEL, and other required tests for measuring teacher aptitude and readiness

Elk Grove High School · English Teacher · Elk Grove, CA

2016 to 2018

Taught English Language arts with common core aligned curriculum to English 10 classes, and AVID

Fairfield High School · English Teacher · Fairfield, CA

2015 to 2016

Taught grade 11 and grade 12 English Language Arts with Common Core aligned ERWC curriculum